Anderson Parra de Paula

Software Engineer

and

ander.pp@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/anderparra



+49 1525 5783758

I believe that software can enable people to be creative and to save a lot of time. I also believe programming languages are just tools that can fit in different ways for different solutions. My goal is to build and deploy simple software that adds great value.

I have 9 years of industry experience on software engineering. I am also experienced in high-scale distributed systems and functional programming.

Experiences

Backend Engineer at SoundCloud

10/2015 - Present (Berlin, Germany)

Member of an agile team responsible for a system that provides accurate financial reporting to all monetization partners and automated calculation of royalty payments, in order to accommodate growth towards +10M monetized tracks in the platform and thousands of new partners.

Senior Software Engineer at Ericsson

10/2014 - 10/2015 (Athlone, Ireland)

Member of an agile team responsible for Ericsson's SON Optimization Manager, providing automatic optimization of radio networks and optimizing multiple network elements and domains in a coordinated, top-down approach. This allowed the integration of multiple technologies (2G, 3G and 4G) and multiple vendors into a single optimization paradigm.

Principal Software Engineer at Amil

07/2011 - 10/2014 (São Paulo, Brazil)

Team leader and member of an agile team responsible for core technical solutions, training and improving the quality of various internal teams. Developed frameworks to increase productivity, abstract complex tasks/concepts and elimination of repeated work.

Senior Software Engineer at Amil

07/2009 - 07/2011 (São Paulo, Brazil)

Developed and maintened a mission-critical high scale service available to all hospitals and clinics nationwide in order to comply with Brazilian government healthcare standards.

Software Engineer at Auster

08/2007 - 07/2009 (São Paulo, Brazil)

Education

Master degree in Computer Science Universidade Federal de São Carlos - Brazil 2012 - 2015

Focused on Distributed Systems and Data Replication. Dissertation titled "A Lightweight Reconfiguration Solution for Paxos".

Specialization in Web Development Universidade Federal de São Carlos - Brazil

2009 - 2010

Bachelor degree in Computer Science

Universidade Anhembi Morumbi - Brazil 2005 - 2008

Skills

Distributed Systems
Data Replication
Web Application
Web Services (SOAP / REST)
Software Tests
Agile

Tools

Java
Scala
JavaScript
Ruby
Python
Node.js
HTML / CSS

SQL
Hadoop
Spark
MongoDB
Docker
Vagrant

AWS